Hi, if you've ever wondered how to massage away a stiff calf, I can show you how.
I'm Sundae, with Natural Sundae.
Now, the first thing you want to do, is make sure your client is relaxed, and the best way to do this, is just rock your client a little bit.
You just rock that client.
You just shake them a little bit, gently of course.
Make sure they're not holding any tension, and that they're fully relaxed.
Then, what you want to do actually, before you massage the calf, you want to massage up in the hamstrings, because if there's any congestion in here.
If this is congested, this congestion is not going to go anywhere, so you need to get the congestion out of the hamstring first, and then work the calves, so real quick, just work the calf.
You can do some basic strokes, gliding all the way up the leg, using the fingers and the palms, very gently, and kneading is also a wonderful way, to massage the hamstrings.
Just do some kneading.
Now, that that's clear, you're free to move to the calf, so what you want to do, is start at the ankle, and move all the way up to the calf, and your fingers can trace that muscle, and actually hold that muscle right in your hand, just like that.
You want to apply a little bit more oil, and actually your palm, is the best part of your hand.
To massage a calf, you can go from your palm, all the way up to your forearm, and even your elbow, as long as you're careful, just like that, and of course, on the other side, using that forearm very gently, getting that ankle, being very careful of that ankle area.
Massaging that calf with that forearm.
You can rotate your forearm, like this, and really get in between those two muscles.
You've got your gastrock right here, and your soleus.
Those are your two calf muscles.
You want to really get in between there.
Separate those muscles, and create a lot of room for the blood to flow, and that is a very basic way, to soothe a sore calf muscle.
I'm Sundae, with Natural Sundae.
Thanks.